<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
    <header>
	
	<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1"/>
	<meta name="copyright" content="2008 by Alexis PARIS"/>
	<meta name="robots" content="all"/>
	<meta name="author" content="Alexis PARIS"/>
	<meta name="subject" content="Java wizard assistant"/>
	<meta name="topic" content="Metas"/>
	<meta name="expires" content="never"/>
	<meta name="keywords" content="Awl Java wizard assistant page"/>
	
	<title><h1>Features of Blackdog</h1></title>
	
    </header> 
    <body>
	<br/>
	<section id="functionnalities" name="">
	    <p>
		<ul>
		    <li><b><u>Audios</u></b> :
			<ul>
			    <li>Management of the main audio formats (mp3, ogg, flac, etc...).</li>
			    <li>Management of web radios.</li>
			    <li>Information about a song :
				<ul>
				    <li>Rate</li>
				    <li>Date of creation</li>
				    <li>Date when the song was last played.</li>
				    <li>Number of time an item was played.</li>
				</ul>

				and of course the traditional pieces of information :
				<ul>
				    <li>Title</li>
				    <li>Artist</li>
				    <li>Album</li>
				    <li>Catégory</li>
				    <li>Track number</li>
				    <li>Author</li>
				    <li>Comment</li>
				</ul>
				Those informations are presents and can be modified even if the format does not supports tags.
			    </li>
			    <li>Modify the caracteristics of song without opening a dialog window.</li>
			    <li>Modify caracteristics of several items at a time.</li>
			    <li>Real-time modifications of the tags of audio files.</li>
			    <li>Move/copy a group of items to another directory.</li>
			</ul>
		    </li>
		    
		    <li><b><u>Readers</u></b> :
			<ul>
			    <li>Could chose the reader to use. Currently, there are two available readers :
				<ul>
				    <li>MPlayer based reader which is the default one.</li>
				    <li>Reader based on the Java audio framework (only allows to play the most commons audio formats).</li>
				</ul>
			    </li>
			</ul>
		    </li>
		    
		    <li><b><u>Editors</u></b> :
			<ul>
			    <li>Playlist editor :
				<ul>
				    <li>Allow to filter on the items of a playlist by entering criterions : allow to find a song fast.</li>
				    <li>Choose which information of the item you want to see in the editor (track number, rate, etc..).</li>
				    <li>Sorting (allow, for example, to sort items according to their rate).</li>
				    <li>Complete playlists by using drag'n drop.</li>
				</ul>
			    </li>
			</ul>
		    </li>
		    
		    <li><b><u>Tools</u></b> :
			<ul>
			    
			    <li>Editor which allow to visualize images relative to the item currently played :
				<ul>
				    <li>Use the images in the directory of the item.</li>
				    <li>Could indicate the default image to use for a song.</li>
				    <li>Search for new images on the web :
					<ul>
					    <li>Get in real-time images found by using the caracteristics of the song.</li>
					    <li>Allow to save images on the directory of the song.</li>
					    <li>Choose the search engine; today, only one plugin is available : it searchs images using Google search engine.<br/>
						Some others search engines will be added in the next months.
					    </li>
					</ul>

					Available parameters :
					<ul>
					    <li>Maximum images found.</li>
					    <li>Choose the size of the images downloaded.</li>
					</ul>
				    </li>
				</ul>
			    </li>
			    
			    <li>Tools that allow to search for the lyrics of a song according to the database of <a href="http://www.leoslyrics.com/">leo'lyrics</a>.<br/>
				As image searchers, anothers lyrics providers will be added later.
			    </li>
			</ul>
		    </li>
		    
		    <li><b><u>Scan</u></b> : <br/>Blackdog only needs to know the directory where you have the habit to store your audio files.<br/>
			When it knows it, you only have to launch another scan and blackdog will automatically adds new items in your audio library.
		    </li>
		</ul>
		
	    </p>
	</section>
    </body>
</document>
